## Vinita Wanere

Melbourne, VIC | 047-893-5022 | vinita.wanere@gmail.com

### Skills

- JIRA
- Salesforce
- Confluence
- User Story Capture
- Agile Ceremony Facilitation
- Egnyte
- MS Office
- Agile Planning
- Sprint Planning
- Technical Writing
- Proposal Writing

### **Education**

Master of Business Administration | University of Pune | 2013 – 2015

Bachelor of Business
Administration | University of
Pune | 2010 – 2013

### **Summary**

Extensive experience as a Business Analyst across banking and financial services with strong agile planning and facilitation experience. A key focus placed on work facilitation, requirements/User Story pure, gap analysis, gap analysis, creating business requirement documentation, stakeholder management, and team leadership. I have also worked as a Bid Manager/Proposal Developer for over 3 years in banking and IT.

Both my experiences ave given me an opportunity to work with various stakeholders and members from different teams, departments and Business Units in Banking, financial Services and IT

## **Work Experience**

WE Wumbo Pty. Ltd. | Business Analyst | August 2022 - March 2022

- Gathering, validating, and documenting requirements using Agile Methodology
- Evaluate, Analyse and Communicate system requirements n a continuing basis partnering with product owner, the designing and the development team
- Close involvement in road map planning, prioritisation and the software development lifecycle
- Closely worked with integration partners to collaborate on various verticals
- Coordinate, review, and edit inputs from a variety of stakeholders from various departments and business units.

Exela Technologies Inc. | Proposal Development and Analyst | May 2022 - July 2022

 Delivery of compliant, professionally produced proposals with customer defined timeframes for various financial and IT products using scrum.

- Complete and review requests for proposal, information, and quotations by capture planning and requirement gathering through RFP/RFI/RFQs.
- Coordinate and review/edit requests for proposal inputs from variety of stakeholders, typically involving contributions from sales, marketing, product teams, finance, information security, legal and delivery.
- Collaborating with other department stakeholders to finalise and prioritise proposals using scrum.
- Creating and executing a proposal plan/scheduling and ensuring compliance.

# Bank of New York Mellon | Lead Analyst | May 2021 - March 2022

- Managed multiple time framed projects in the Asset Servicing
   Sales Support Team in banking
- Delivery of compliant professionally produced projects within the deadlines.
- Coordinate, review and edit inputs from a variety of stakeholders from various departments and business units.
- Creating and executing a project plan/schedule ensuring compliance, which is sensitive for banking.
- Define agile delivery roadmap which included: User story capture, team planning and business acceptance.

# Exela Technologies Inc. | Proposal Development and Analyst | October 2019 - May 2021

- Complete and review requests for proposals, information and quotations in financial and IT products using Agile Methodology.
- Issuing writing assignments to each Subject Matter Expert (SME) with detailed instructions and deadline information.
- Contributing to the analyst relations team to gather the required information.

### FIS Global | Business Analyst | May 2015 - October 2019

- Gathering, validating and documenting the Business Requirement Documents (BRDs) for financial technology using Agile Methodology.
- Evaluate, analyse and communicate system requirements on a continuing basis by partnering with stakeholders across business units.
- Creating functional specifications for financial solutions offered by FIS Global and full time involvement in the software development lifecycle.
- Author and update internal and external documentation, and formerly initiate and deliver requirements and documentation required for the financial services provided by FIS Global
- Conducting weekly showcases for product enhancements and creating process flows.

 Was involved in capture planning, requirement gathering, release management, prioritisation, retrospections, and creating BRDs etc.

## **Projects**

# Advantages of Systematic Investment Plans in Long Term Investments

This project was done under the partial fulfilment of the requirement for the award of BBA in Finance

 To study systematic investment plans for long-term growth and the process of staying with a plan and engaging with the entire process of long term investments

#### Study of Computation of Income Under the Head Salary

This project was done under the partial fulfilment of the requirement for the award of MBA in Finance

 To understand the concept of salary income and components forming part of salary for individuals and to study the process of computation of tax under the head salary, tax liability, perquisites and their valuations and deductions.

### Certifications

- Proposal Writing and Management | Udemy | July 2022
- Postgraduate Certificate in Digital Marketing | Symbiosis Institute of Distance Learning | 2019 - 2020
- Basics of Security Markets | Bombay Stock Exchange Limited
   | May 2018
- Trade Lifecycle | Silver Brook Learning Centre | July 2015
- FIM Tech Pro | Stratadigm Education and Training Pvt. Ltd. |
   June 2015